# firstName: "Grayson", lastName: "Gilmore"

Email

gilmoreg@live.com

Folio

http://gilmoreg.com

**GitHub** 

https://github.com/gilmoreg

inkedIn

/in/graysongilmore

#### **Profile**

I've been on a winding journey, from network operations technician to university professor, but I am finally coming home to my first love: writing software. I learned full stack web development and built my portfolio in less than six months while working full time. I'm excited to join a team where I can contribute and continue to grow as a developer!

#### Skill Set

**Server Side:** Node.js, Express, Python Flask and Django, MongoDB, Passport, GraphQL, Serverless

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, Angular, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Responsive design

Testing: Jest, Mocha, Chai, Enzyme, Pytest

**DevOps:** Heroku, Docker, Travis CI, AWS Lightsail, Digital Ocean

## **Projects**

gilmoreg.com

# Condictor • http://condictor.gilmoreg.com • Github repo

A lightweight helpdesk issue tracker. Built with the helpdesk analyst's needs in mind, aiming toward "everything you need, nothing you don't." The back end is a Node/Express server using GraphQL and MongoDB, hosted on Heroku as a Docker container. The client is a React/Redux single page app.

## Referendus • http://referendus.gilmoreg.com • Github repo

A lightweight reference/bibliography manager. Choose between three popular reference formats on the fly and copy a rich text formatted bibliography to the clipboard for use in your writing. Built with Node, MongoDB, Passport, and Angular (version 4). Hosted on Heroku as a Docker container.

## Lego Collector • https://gilmoreg.github.io/legocollector • Github repo

Track Amazon stock levels for lego sets. The back end is a Python/Flask application using a Postgresql database via Sqlalchemy. An AWS Lambda function routinely calls an update endpoint to refresh the stock data. The client is a React/Redux single page app.

#### Steam Battle • http://steam-battle.gilmoreg.com • Github repo

Compare Steam profiles and declare a winner! Built with React/Redux and Google Cloud Functions.

#### Open Source

**Habitica**: Contributed PRs to increase test coverage

#### **Education**

## Thinkful • Fullstack Web Development, Jan - May 2017

Completed intensive, six-month course on modern full-stack JavaScript development. Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

# Work History

# Northern Illinois University • Visiting Assistant Professor, 2016 - 2017

Developed and taught both graduate and undergraduate courses, mentored graduate students.

## Boston College • John Marshall Postdoctoral Fellow, 2015 - 2016

Developed and maintained the website for the John Marshall Project (Adobe Experience Manager). Jumpstarted and directed the JMP Undergraduate Fellowship program. Taught freshman and junior level undergraduate courses.

# American Fiber Systems • Network Operations Technician, 2003 - 2008

Provided network monitoring and troubleshooting for a nationwide fiber optic network. CCNA and Network+ certified.